Present Day
Present Time
And you don't seem to understand
A shame you seemed an honest man
And all the fears you hold so dear
Will turn to whisper in your ear
And you know what they say might hurt you
And you know that it means so much
And you don't even feel a thing
I am falling, I am fading
I have lost it all
I am falling, I am fading, I am drowning
Help me to breathe
I am hurting, I have lost it all
I am losing
Help me to breathe
Why? Why won't you come?
I wish you would come here...
Look! Look at that!
Why you should do that...
...is something you should figure out for yourself.
Gotcha!
Hey, cut it out!
Why?
Don't!
What's the problem? Don't play hard to get!
Come on, let's go someplace happy.
I...
...don't need to stay in a place like this.
What the hell?
What happened?!
W-We don't know anything! W-We've got nothing to do with this!
She came outta nowhere...
Oh, no...
Damn it...
If you stay in a place like this...
...you might not be able to connect.
What a racket...
Can't you be quiet?
Everybody, hurry...
Juri, don't make such a big deal about it.
Yeah, it's just some stupid prank.
B-But...
It'll be okay.
Lain?
Did you get one, too?
Get what?
E-mail!
E-mail?
From Yomoda Chisa!
I... I'm not very good with computers.
You should at least check your mail once a day.
Well, it's up to you, I guess.
Lain's such a baby.
Why is she crying?
Because she got an e-mail from Yomoda Chisa, that's why!
Chisa? Who's that?
She was in class D.
She killed herself last week by jumping off a building in Shibuya.
Come on, the teacher told everybody!
It's not just Juri.
Lots of people have gotten mail from her this week.
But she's...
Right. You shouldn't be getting mail from a dead girl.
But there it is.
What's it like when you die?
It really hurts. :)
Powering up... Working...
Just a little longer...
Log in.
Who are you?
Lain. Please say your name.
La-i-n.
Accepted.
You must be Lain.
Lain has mail.
From who?
Yomoda Chisa.
Do you wish to read your mail?
Hello, how are you?
Hello.
How are you?
Lain, I walked home with you just once. Do you remember?
I have only given up my body.
By doing this, I can explain to you that I am still alive.
I wanted to let you know this, Lain, so I sent this e-mail to you.
Do you understand? It's okay if you can't right now.
You will all understand soon. Everyone will.
Why did you die?
Rumor at school has it that this is a prank e-mail,
but I want you to know that it isn't, Lain.
Why? Why did you die?
God is here.
Huh?
God...
I ate lunch late today. I'm done.
Mom?
Yes?
I got an e-mail.
From a girl who killed herself last week.
What is it, Lain?
It's certainly unusual to see you in here.
I...
I was wondering if you could buy me a new Navi...
Finally caught the bug, huh?
You're in junior high now.
Your friends are leaving you in the dust, right?
I keep telling you that you should use a better machine.
You know, Lain, in this world,
whether it's here in the real world or in the Wired,
people connect to each other, and that's how societies function.
Even a girl like you can make friends right off the bat, Lain.
There's nothing to be afraid of.
I wonder why your mother can't understand that?
I'm not scared.
But why bring up your Navi all of a sudden?
There's a friend I want to see.
What happened?
Damn it...
We apologize for the inconvenience, ladies and gentlemen.
The train is currently stopped due to an accident.
What?
Was someone hit?
I can't believe this...
Miss Iwakura.
Yes, ma'am.
This will be on the test.
Come to the Wired as soon as you can.
Chisa?
Where are you?
Wait!
nan no tsumi mo nai hazu na no ni
Although I must be innocent,
nanraka no batsu wo uketeru
now I am punished.
jibun de maita tane de mo nai no ni
I wasn't the one who sowed those seeds, but nevertheless
sakimidareta hana tsumasareru
I have to pull up the flowers that bloomed from them.
shiranai koto to mo ienai ga
I can't say I didn't know about it,
katabou katsuida oboe wa nai
but I don't remember taking any part in it.
jiyuu wo takaku kawasareta ki mo suru ga
I think my freedom cost me dearly,
kokoro made yasuku utta oboe wa nai
but I don't remember selling my soul so cheaply.
Hey Hey kutabatte osaraba suru made
Hey hey, until I die and say farewell...
Hey Hey dare no te ni mo kakaranai
Hey hey... no one can touch me.
tooi yoru wo urotsuiteiru
You probably don't know
shiranai darou eien no narazu monotachi wo
the eternal outlaws prowling in the distant night.