Present Day
Present Time
And you don't seem to understand
A shame you seemed an honest man
And all the fears you hold so dear
Will turn to whisper in your ear
And you know what they say might hurt you
And you know that it means so much
And you don't even feel a thing
I am falling, I am fading
I have lost it all
I am falling, I am fading, I am drowning
Help me to breathe
I am hurting, I have lost it all
I am losing
Help me to breathe
There is only one truth. God.
Yes. Me.
Isn't that right, Lain?
You're God?
Yes. I am God.
Why are you God? I don't understand.
You're dead, aren't you? A dead human.
Somebody like that can't be God, can they?
I realized that I had no need for a body.
To die is merely to abandon the flesh.
That's... That's just what Chisa said.
I don't need to stay here.
I suppose she did, at that.
I caused the protocol that governs the Wired to evolve.
Yeah. That's what you did.
But a protocol is just an agreement.
Yes, but I incorporated code that operates on a higher phase.
So?
There is compressed information mixed into the protocol.
What kind of information?
Human memories. Mine.
The thoughts, history, memories, and emotions of the man named Eiri Masami.
What does that mean?
I can live forever as an anonymous entity in the Wired,
and will be able to rule it with information.
What do you think a being like that should be called?
A god.
There is no God.
Yes. Even if I were an omnipresent being and could influence others,
with no one to worship me, I am no god.
But you had them. Or made them, I should say.
Knights.
You no longer need a body, Lain.
That's a lie!
Talk about lame!
Some people are like that, I guess.
So I said, go ahead and do it.
Anyway...
Hey, look at this!
Isn't it cute?
It was really cheap!
At that place next door?
Yeah, over there!
Let's go, let's go!
Sure, we don't have anything after school today.
Hey, you're right.
Let's go!
Stand!
Bow!
All right, close your books.
I... I'm real!
I'm alive!
I'm here.
Why is this happening?
Was it something I did?
I always tried to keep something like this from happening.
I always tried not to say anything weird.
Can it be true?
I'm not supposed to have a body?
That's right, Lain.
You're not needed in the real world.
I'm home.
Dad?
This is goodbye, Miss Lain.
You must have figured it out by now. Our work here is finished.
It was only for a short time, but I know I didn't do enough for you.
You're now free to become anything you want.
No, you were free all along.
I wasn't given permission to say goodbye, but I loved you.
It's not that I enjoyed playing house...
Maybe I envied a being like you.
Goodbye.
Wait!
Don't leave me alone!
Alone? You're not alone.
If you connect to the Wired, everyone will welcome you.
That's the sort of being you were.
I'm not alone.
Do you want to do anything, Lain?
This is your world, Lain.
Who are the Knights? They're the ones who made the fake me, right?
I'm not sure.
No, it's possible.
They say you can trace the origin of the
Knights of the Eastern Calculus back to the Knights Templar.
They've used that invisible human network, the collective unconscious,
since long before the Wired was born.
What do you want to do, Lain?
Knights...
Who are the Knights?
You really want to know, don't you, Lain?
The Wired's God is a god because He has worshipers.
Hey, Taro, let's go someplace else.
This place has gotten boring.
Yeah. Why not come over to my house?
You don't need to come, Masayuki.
What's the big idea?
Taro says he doesn't wanna hang out with a little kid like you.
Wha...?
You're as much a kid as I am, Myu-Myu!
It's okay for a girl! Everybody knows that younger is better for girls.
Right, Taro?
What's that?
What's up, Taro? Is there something on the Net News?
It's a list.
Huh? What kind of list?
What's a list of Knights members doing on the Net News?
Y-Yes?
Please remain silent.
W-Who are you?
Time to pay the piper, all right?
W-What do you mean?
Mom, I got killed!
Mom!
It's your turn, Mom! If you don't hurry up, I'm gonna keep playing!
Okay, Mom?
I'm gonna take 'em out!
A series of suicides occurred today all over the world,
and each country's Information Control Ministry
and police departments have begun investigating the cause.
Each victim was involved in network-related work,
and sources tell us that it appears that they were all members
of a fraternal order known as the "Knights."
Why did you do it?
It was a request from our client.
You hunted down all the Knights in the world.
Our associates are now on their way to dispose of them.
But why?
The Wired can't be allowed to be a special world.
It can only be a field that functions as a sub-system reinforcing the real world.
But still...
You can't be allowed to exist in the Wired, either.
But here you are, safe and sound.
Some god or whatever must be protecting you.
Eiri Masami's residual thought program
will eventually be disinfected from the Wired.
Our client is working on a total rewrite of the Protocol Seven code.
We have no need for gods.
Right. Not in the Wired or in the real world.
We still haven't figured out what you are.
But I love you.
Love certainly is a strange emotion, isn't it?
What will you do?
Well, let me think...
You don't have anyone to pray to you now.
I can't be a god, then. But I haven't lost all of them.
If only one believer remains, I can still be a god.
Who?
Come, now... You, Lain.
It's because of me that you can stay yourself.
You were originally born in the Wired.
The legend of the Wired. The heroine of the Wired's fairy tales.
Liar.
The real world's Iwakura Lain is merely a hologram of her.
A homunculus of artificial ribosomes.
You never had a body to begin with.
That's a lie.
A fake family. Fake friends. Yes, it was all a lie.
That's a lie...
That's all a lie...
Poor Lain... She's all alone.
But I'm here. The man who loves you is here.
You should be able to love me, the man who sent you to this world...
I am your creator.
Love me.
All right, Lain?
The other...
The other me, she's...
That isn't another you. It's the real you.
Like it matters!
nan no tsumi mo nai hazu na no ni
Although I must be innocent,
nanraka no batsu wo uketeru
now I am punished.
jibun de maita tane de mo nai no ni
I wasn't the one who sowed those seeds, but nevertheless
sakimidareta hana tsumasareru
I have to pull up the flowers that bloomed from them.
shiranai koto to mo ienai ga
I can't say I didn't know about it,
katabou katsuida oboe wa nai
but I don't remember taking any part in it.
jiyuu wo takaku kawasareta ki mo suru ga
I think my freedom cost me dearly,
kokoro made yasuku utta oboe wa nai
but I don't remember selling my soul so cheaply.
Hey Hey kutabatte osaraba suru made
Hey hey, until I die and say farewell...
Hey Hey dare no te ni mo kakaranai
Hey hey... no one can touch me.
tooi yoru wo urotsuiteiru
You probably don't know
shiranai darou eien no narazu monotachi wo
the eternal outlaws prowling in the distant night.