Present Day
Present Time
And you don't seem to understand
A shame you seemed an honest man
And all the fears you hold so dear
Will turn to whisper in your ear
And you know what they say might hurt you
And you know that it means so much
And you don't even feel a thing
I am falling, I am fading
I have lost it all
I am falling, I am fading, I am drowning
Help me to breathe
I am hurting, I have lost it all
I am losing
Help me to breathe
No, it's nothing as ambiguous as "memory"
Am I me?
Lain is Lain
I wish you'd come here...
I don't need to stay here.
You'll have to excuse me. All this talking has worn me out.
I've never seen one before!
Iwakura Lain. Are you and the Lain of the Wired one and the same?
I've seen you before. In the Wired.
Peeping Tom
Come
Poor Lain...
Hey, I'm Lain, aren't I?
No!
No, you're not!
That's right, Lain. You're not needed in the real world.
I'm committing suicide!
Why? Why are you warm?
Why do I have to feel the heat from your body?
Yes. I'm God.
How could you?
Lain, you'd have more fun if you were a little more sociable.
She's changed, all right.
Are you okay?
Lately... You've been slipping back to your old self, Lain.
Are you okay? Lain, I...
Lain, I'm sorry! It's all our fault! Are you okay, Lain?
Glad to hear it.
Are you tired?
Yes.
You're incredible...
So, you've loaded an emulator of that Navi into your own brain.
It's dangerous to subject yourself to that much information all at once.
At your current capacity, you'll overflow.
Am I a machine?
Don't talk about me like I'm a machine.
I didn't mean to.
This is basically a software problem.
Lain, you're software.
You're not hardware.
Software?
Yes. An executable program with a body.
Be quiet...
Be quiet!
Chisa!
Chisa, we walked home together just once, right?
I understand. I finally understand what you told me.
Lain...
It's easy to die, Lain.
Right?
There's nothing easy about dying.
Sure it is!
Lain, you already have a tool that will let you do it.
What do you...
The safety's already off.
The trigger's heavy, so hold it with both hands and pull it with your thumb.
A girl isn't strong enough.
What, you still want to stay in the real world?
Hey, that's not fair. You called me here, remember?
I... I never...
Bodies are meaningless.
You're wrong.
Lain.
What is this?
I thought that maybe we could meet after school and I could introduce you.
This guy's pretty cute!
And then those rumors about you and that teacher...
I think if you get a boyfriend, everyone will know they're a lie.
See you tomorrow. We'll talk about it then.
'Bye!
It's not a lie.
W-Who's there?
Who's there?!
Lain?
W-What?
What's happened to you? You...
It wasn't me.
I never peeked at your secrets, Arisu,
and I never sent those secrets out onto the Wired.
It was you, Lain! I saw you!
That isn't me.
It looks like I'm not the only me. Some other me did it.
What're you talking about?
You might not be the only Arisu, either.
But no matter how often I say I didn't do it, you'll believe that I did.
So I'll make it so that it never happened.
I've been working really hard to be able to do that.
What do you mean?
I don't need devices anymore.
It looks like I've already destroyed the border
between the Wired and the real world.
I can go anyplace I want to now.
So I came here.
I should be able to undo something that happened!
Lain...
I...
I'm scared...
I'm scared!
Arisu!
Arisu! Good morning!
Good morning.
What's up, Arisu? Why are you depressed?
Oh, is it that time of the month?
Hey, you ever hear of"delicacy"?
Come on, I was only...
Juri, I don't think I can go through with it today.
Huh? Go through with what?
What? Didn't you send me a CU-mail yesterday?
No, I didn't send you anything yesterday.
You're sure acting strange today, Arisu.
Arisu!
Oh, that teacher... He sure is hot!
Yeah! But rumor has it that he's seeing an 8th-grader!
What, are you serious? That's gross!
Um... Listen, I...
What is it?
A-About that teacher... and me...
Is there something between that teacher and you?
Do you like him or something?
Sorry, you're too late!
Yeah! He already has a girlfriend.
That's not like you, Arisu.
Yeah, she sure is acting strange today.
Lain! Good morning!
Hurry it up!
Come on, Lain!
Lain!
Lain, you...
Lain, you smiled...
nan no tsumi mo nai hazu na no ni
Although I must be innocent,
nanraka no batsu wo uketeru
now I am punished.
jibun de maita tane de mo nai no ni
I wasn't the one who sowed those seeds, but nevertheless
sakimidareta hana tsumasareru
I have to pull up the flowers that bloomed from them.
shiranai koto to mo ienai ga
I can't say I didn't know about it,
katabou katsuida oboe wa nai
but I don't remember taking any part in it.
jiyuu wo takaku kawasareta ki mo suru ga
I think my freedom cost me dearly,
kokoro made yasuku utta oboe wa nai
but I don't remember selling my soul so cheaply.
Hey Hey kutabatte osaraba suru made
Hey hey, until I die and say farewell...
Hey Hey dare no te ni mo kakaranai
Hey hey... no one can touch me.
tooi yoru wo urotsuiteiru
You probably don't know
shiranai darou eien no narazu monotachi wo
the eternal outlaws prowling in the distant night.