Present Day
Present Time
And you don't seem to understand
A shame you seemed an honest man
And all the fears you hold so dear
Will turn to whisper in your ear
And you know what they say might hurt you
And you know that it means so much
And you don't even feel a thing
I am falling, I am fading
I have lost it all
I am falling, I am fading, I am drowning
Help me to breathe
I am hurting, I have lost it all
I am losing
Help me to breathe
Oh, okay. So that's how it works.
I had no idea the world was this simple.
I always thought the world was such a big and scary place,
but once you figure it out, it's all so easy.
See? I told you it would be.
That's terrible, Lain!
I can't believe you just said that!
Lain...
I know, but it's true!
That's the first I've heard of it!
What does it mean?
Acting all high and mighty again, huh, Lain?
That reminds me, Juri.
What?
You should just rewrite bad memories.
But that's...
Unbelievable...
Aw, come on!
People only have substance within the memories of others.
That's why there were all kinds of me's.
There weren't a lot of me's,
I was just inside all sorts of people, that's all.
Really, no kidding?
Come on, Taro, who are you talking to?
W-What's up?
You know, I...
I kissed an angel.
Taro...
Lain...
Protocol Seven is expected to allow the seamless sharing of information
between the Wired and the real world.
And now, the following message...
Let's all love Lain!
All the functions of the human body, without exception,
can be put into words and described in materialistic terms.
The body is nothing but a machine.
If the physical limitations of the body restrict mankind's evolution,
it would be as if the fall of the species called "man"
had already been decided by a God that doesn't even exist.
The information etched inside humans isn't only that which
they themselves have acquired as individuals.
This species called man is connected to his predecessors,
and information has accumulated within him.
If that information isn't shared, it's meaningless. Mere data.
Mankind can evolve. Evolve by their own power.
But to do that, they must first know what they truly are.
What do you think you are?
Originally, people were connected to each other.
All I've done is to make things as they once were.
That's what you have done, Lain.
So you can do anything you want.
I thought you quit smoking.
Why is this happening? We did exactly what we were told to do!
It means that our client wasn't the only one who thought that
those computer geeks playing "secret society" would be trouble.
What do you mean?
Our client was in contact with Masami Eiri.
No, maybe Eiri was behind it all.
Enough about Eiri, okay?
The guy's dead.
He's not dead.
Whether he had a body or not never mattered.
It never mattered.
Are you serious?
Payment for services rendered, huh?
You've been using us, haven't you?!
Interpret it any way you like.
You want us to leave town, huh? And go where?
I suppose a place with no power lines that isn't covered by a satellite.
There's no place like that on Earth, and you know it!
If you're going to run, you'll have to find a place like that.
What's going to happen?
What are you planning to do
by connecting the Wired to the real world without any devices?
Something wonderful is going to happen.
I'm looking forward to it. Aren't you?
What the...?
What's wrong?!
What are you seeing?!
Hey!
Iwakura
Lain?
No!
This is Lain's room?
Lain?
L-Lain!
A... risu?
What did you do?
Nothing.
I've just been watching.
Watching what?
I... I thought I had gone crazy.
But I didn't!
Lain! Why did you leave only me?
Why did you only leave my memories alone?
Why do I always have to remember all those horrible things?!
Do you hate me that much, Lain?
I... I can't take this!
No... You've got it all wrong, Arisu.
I didn't want to hurt you.
Liar! Look at what you've done!
But you're okay, aren't you, Arisu?
You were my friend, even without connecting with me, Arisu.
What are you saying?
You're my only friend, Arisu.
Even without connecting with me.
"Connecting"? W-What do you mean?
Connecting to me... And everyone...
S-Stop!
I love you, Arisu.
Do you know what you're saying, Lain?
Humans were originally connected at an unconscious level.
I reconnected them, that's all.
Lain, you?
I don't do anything.
It doesn't matter which is real, this side or the other.
I was in both.
I'm a program designed to destroy the barrier
between the Wired and the real world.
You're a program, Lain?
You and everyone else, Arisu, you're just applications.
The truth is, you don't need bodies.
You're wrong.
I don't really understand what you're saying, but I think you're wrong.
Your body's cold, but you're alive, Lain.
Mine, too. See?
See? My heart...
...it's beating.
Beating... Beating...
But why? Why's it beating like that?
Because I'm scared. It's pounding because I'm scared.
But you're smiling, Arisu.
Yeah, I guess I am. But I'm scared.
I've always been scared. I wonder why?
I wonder why?
Because she's afraid of losing her body.
All sensations are caused by impulses in the brain.
You just need to block the unpleasant impulses.
Select only the happy, pleasant ones.
Really?
Lain? Who are you talking to?
If you really love her, why don't you connect with her?
I'm not sure.
Lain? Who are you talking to?
Lain!
You must have a bug.
Very well. I'll take my time and give you a thorough debugging.
Come, Lain.
What I don't understand is you, God.
Y-You're... talking to God?
What don't you understand, Lain?
What you did was to remove devices from the Wired.
Phones, television, the network...
Without those, you couldn't have done anything.
Yes. Those are things which accompanied human evolution.
Humans who are further evolved than others
have a right to greater abilities.
Who gave you those rights?
The program that inserted code synched to the Earth's
characteristic frequency into the Protocol Seven code,
which would raise the collective unconscious to the conscious level.
Did you really come up with the idea by yourself?
What are you getting at?
No, it can't be... It can't be!
Are you telling me that there really is a God?!
It doesn't matter. With no body, you can't understand.
It's a lie! I... I'm omnipotent!
I gave you a body here in the real world!
You were omnipresent, scattered through the Wired! I gave you an ego!
You mean to say...
If that's true of me, what about you?
I'm different! I...
The Wired isn't an upper layer of the real world.
What do you mean?
Inside the Wired, you were God, all right.
But what about before the Wired was created?
You're just an acting God, standing in for someone
who was waiting for the Wired to reach its current state.
An "acting" God?!
That can't be!
Arisu!
A body doesn't mean anything to you, right?
No!
nan no tsumi mo nai hazu na no ni
Although I must be innocent,
nanraka no batsu wo uketeru
now I am punished.
jibun de maita tane de mo nai no ni
I wasn't the one who sowed those seeds, but nevertheless
sakimidareta hana tsumasareru
I have to pull up the flowers that bloomed from them.
shiranai koto to mo ienai ga
I can't say I didn't know about it,
katabou katsuida oboe wa nai
but I don't remember taking any part in it.
jiyuu wo takaku kawasareta ki mo suru ga
I think my freedom cost me dearly,
kokoro made yasuku utta oboe wa nai
but I don't remember selling my soul so cheaply.
Hey Hey kutabatte osaraba suru made
Hey hey, until I die and say farewell...
Hey Hey dare no te ni mo kakaranai
Hey hey... no one can touch me.
tooi yoru wo urotsuiteiru
You probably don't know
shiranai darou eien no narazu monotachi wo
the eternal outlaws prowling in the distant night.