Present Day
Present Time
And you don't seem to understand
A shame you seemed an honest man
And all the fears you hold so dear
Will turn to whisper in your ear
And you know what they say might hurt you
And you know that it means so much
And you don't even feel a thing
I am falling, I am fading
I have lost it all
I am falling, I am fading, I am drowning
Help me to breathe
I am hurting, I have lost it all
I am losing
Help me to breathe
I... I'm confused again.
Am I here? Or am I there?
Over there, I'm everywhere. I know that.
I'm connected there, after all.
Right?
But where is the real me?
Oh, right. There is no real me.
I only exist inside those people who are aware of my existence.
But this me that's talking right now...
It's me, isn't it?
This me that's talking... This me... Who is it?
Arisu!
A body doesn't mean anything to you, right?
Arisu...
No!
I mess up everything I try to do for you, huh, Arisu?
Honest, I...
Arisu!
I'm sorry...
Arisu, I'm sorry...
I'm done.
Hey, you didn't clean your plate.
She says she's on a diet.
Tell the whole world, why don't you?
Oh, I might get a package today. It's C.O.D.
If it comes, pay for it, okay?
Computer parts again?
Hey...
Yes?
No, it's nothing.
Arisu!
Arisu! We're going out tonight, right?
Cyberia! Cyberia!
Oh. Sure, why not?
I'd better mail her, then.
Arisu? Mail who?
Oh, don't tell me you want her to come along again...
"Her"?
Chisa?
Yeah. Yomoda Chisa.
Arisu, you talked us into taking her to Cyberia once,
but it's like she just didn't care.
Inviting her is pointless.
Oh, I get it...
Huh?
It's nothing.
I just thought of something strange.
Something strange?
If you don't remember something, it never happened.
Don't remember?
If you aren't remembered, you never existed.
Who are you talking about?
Like I said. Nobody.
Come on, we'd better hit the books.
Arisu!
Go!
Man, I gotta do it again?
Come on, one more time!
Hurry up!
Wait for me!
You're such a sucker!
Mail?
What is it?
Who's that girl?!
I don't know.
Now what?
Hey, nice machine!
Mine's pretty tricked out, too.
Come on! Hurry!
Come on! Come on!
Mom's waiting!
Okay, okay... Bye.
Let's go!
Wait! Shoot for it again!
Hurry up, Taro!
No fair! Shoot for it again!
I'll quit. I'll quit that dump.
The crap they make me do...
They all underestimate me...
Oh, well.
I'm gonna quit... I'm gonna quit!
I'm gonna quit!
I'm gonna quit today for sure!
What isn't remembered never happened
Memory is merely a record
You just need to rewrite that record
Is that true?
Present Day
Present Time
Why are you crying?
Because you deleted yourself from everyone's memory?
But isn't that what you wanted?
Yes, but...
No one is dying, and no one is being hurt.
And no one hates you.
Yes, but...
Dead people's information isn't leaking out of the Wired anymore.
So Lain doesn't need to be anywhere anymore.
This is what you wanted, isn't it?
You sound just like him.
Him?
That man never existed now.
Even if he does, he won't get any ideas into his head about being God.
I'm nowhere now...
If I'm nowhere, who am I?
Where am I?
You yourself said it.
The Wired isn't an upper layer of the real world.
That's what that man was mistaken about.
A network is a field to pass along information.
Information doesn't stand still there.
Information functions by always being in motion.
Really?
People's memories aren't just personal or one part of the history of humanity.
No, not even the shared unconscious.
Do you think that humans could create something that could store
memory that's that vast?
The Wired was just connected to something else...
But where was it connected to?
Do people really need to know that?
Look at how far they've come without knowing.
The human world creates and prays to its various gods,
and humans convince themselves, "This is how the world is."
I don't like how you're saying this.
Either way, it's Lain that's saying it. Me.
You understand that, right?
Oh, right... Lain was never a person, was she?
Lain is omnipresent, existing everywhere.
Lain watches quietly.
Right, Lain is God!
No...
You're wrong!
It'd be so much easier if you became God.
I think it'd be a lot easier than being a human.
You wouldn't have to do anything. Just stand there and watch.
No one would look down on Lain.
No one would hate Lain.
That's...
Hey, Lain, let's start everything over again from the beginning!
I mean, you did go and reset everything, after all...
Stop it!
Then what are you, Lain?
I...
Where am I?
Come, Lain.
Dad?
You don't need to wear that anymore, Lain.
Dad, do you know?
What?
I... Everyone, I...
You love them?
Isn't that right?
Lain, I'll make us some nice tea next time.
Hey, with some madeleines! Definitely. They're great!
So memories aren't only of the past, are they?
They can be of right now, or even of tomorrow.
Unbelievable!
Isn't it? But hang on a second...
I listened to what you had to say.
Very patiently, I might add.
I get to pick the curtains for the bedroom, right?
Yes, ma'am.
Anything you say.
All right, then. That's a good student.
Something wrong?
No.
Sorry, could you wait here a minute?
Hey, what're you...
Hello.
Have we met before? We have, haven't we?
Did you go to the school I was a student teacher at?
No, that can't be it...
Let me think...
Pleased to meet you.
Huh?
Pleased to meet you. We haven't met before.
Oh. Well, I'm pleased to meet you, then.
I'm Arisu.
Strange name, huh? I'm kind of embarrassed about it.
What's yours?
Lain.
Lain?
A friend of yours?
No, I thought she was someone else.
Well, goodbye, Lain.
Maybe we'll run into each other again someday.
Bye.
Bye, Lain.
You're right. We can see each other anytime.
I'm here, so I'll be with you forever.
nan no tsumi mo nai hazu na no ni
Although I must be innocent,
nanraka no batsu wo uketeru
now I am punished.
jibun de maita tane de mo nai no ni
I wasn't the one who sowed those seeds, but nevertheless
sakimidareta hana tsumasareru
I have to pull up the flowers that bloomed from them.
shiranai koto to mo ienai ga
I can't say I didn't know about it,
katabou katsuida oboe wa nai
but I don't remember taking any part in it.
jiyuu wo takaku kawasareta ki mo suru ga
I think my freedom cost me dearly,
kokoro made yasuku utta oboe wa nai
but I don't remember selling my soul so cheaply.
Hey Hey kutabatte osaraba suru made
Hey hey, until I die and say farewell...
Hey Hey dare no te ni mo kakaranai
Hey hey... no one can touch me.
tooi yoru wo urotsuiteiru
You probably don't know
shiranai darou eien no narazu monotachi wo
the eternal outlaws prowling in the distant night.