Present Day
Present Time
And you don't seem to understand
A shame you seemed an honest man
And all the fears you hold so dear
Will turn to whisper in your ear
And you know what they say might hurt you
And you know that it means so much
And you don't even feel a thing
I am falling, I am fading
I have lost it all
I am falling, I am fading, I am drowning
Help me to breathe
I am hurting, I have lost it all
I am losing
Help me to breathe
What are you scared of?
Just try it for a little bit.
Cyberia?
I don't come here because I want to.
10,000 yen?! What a ripoff!
The going price is only around 4000!
We call it Accela.
It's not exactly a drug.
but you have to jump through the same kinds of hoops to get it.
I feel...
accelerated.
Hurry up, come to me.
No, that's not it.
I don't have any mail...
I don't get it...
Oh.
I thought somebody was here.
Who?
Your imaginary friend.
Or something like that.
You're gonna be late again.
Lain!
Good morning.
See what I mean? It couldn't have been her.
You think so? But...
What?
Cut it out. I feel sorry for her.
It's nothing. Come on, let's go.
Okay.
But...
Oh, let it go.
Have you gotten any more e-mail?
E-mail?
From Chisa.
Oh, that. No, I haven't gotten any more.
You got that prank mail, too, Lain?
What?
Really?
I was just curious.
Huh?
You know, maybe she does look a little like her...
Lain, what were you doing last night?
Yeah, yeah!
Come on, I'm telling you it wasn't her!
I guess not. She doesn't look like her at all.
What?
There was a girl at Cyberia last night who looked just like you, Lain.
Cyberia?
We finally worked up the nerve to go there last night.
Come on, it wasn't such a big deal.
Yeah, right, you were the one who was all nervous!
Oh. It's a club. Young people go there at night.
There was a girl there who looked a little like you, Lain.
Last night, I...
We know. It wasn't you.
We didn't get a good look at her,
but she had on these wild clothes, and chewed people out left and right.
Yeah, it was like she was your total opposite.
But she did look like her...
Hey, I know! Let's take her with us next time!
You want to make sure, huh?
Cut it out! You're just making fun of her.
I bet when a girl like Lain goes to a club, her personality does a 180!
Oh. Maybe Lain would liven up a bit.
Right! Let's go, Lain!
It might be fun.
You'd have more fun if you were a little more sociable, Lain.
Right, Lain?
Accela, a type of smart supplement,
uses nano-mechanisms to oscillate at a specific frequency within the body,
triggering the secretion of a specific hormone.
It is said that when secreted, this hormone affects the time-sense
of the human mind, making it seem as if one's awareness is accelerated.
Not only the consciousness, but the workings of the brain itself are altered,
multiplying the brain's operational capacity by 2 to 12 times.
The nano-mechanism itself is destroyed by digestive juices within 24 hours,
but it is unknown how long its effectiveness...
Let's have fun at Cyberia tonight! From, Arisu
I'll pass on tonight.
Everyone is connected.
Is this your place?
Great! I have a delivery for you.
I'll start unloading it. Could you get the gate for me?
Could you sign this, please?
This thing is so cool!
I wish I had one of these...
Thanks.
All this is yours?
I'm not sure.
Then you don't know what this is?
It's a top of the line Navi!
Fully loaded, too!
With this kind of horsepower, you can move around freely
without any stress at all, even in the Wired.
I use a home-brew system, myself. It doesn't hold a candle to this.
No, it's not like that. I don't know anything about it, either.
You will soon enough.
Have a good one.
Your Navi came, right?
Get that mess cleaned up soon, all right? It's in the way.
I'll set it up for you after dinner.
This Navi's good enough that I'd want to take it for a spin.
Dad...
I want you to set it up now.
Hey, why are you in such a hurry?
Lain...
I'll do it.
You can't keep using that children's Navi forever.
For communication, you need a powerful system
that will mature alongside your relationships with people.
Understand, Lain?
Come here.
Register yourself as the machine's user.
Try talking to it.
Hello, Navi.
Now this Navi's yours, Lain.
You can show off to your friends now.
Oops.
Hey, Mika. Something wrong?
Navi, do I have mail?
Lain has no mail.
Lain, where are you? Everybody's waiting! You have to come!
Why won't you come?
Okay, turn left at that corner!
Then go straight ahead.
See it?
Yeah.
We're in the basement! Got it?
Hey! You!
You're blocking the stairs.
Sorry.
If you do it that way,
you'll get spotted by the Info-Guard Center right off the bat!
What's the big deal? I'd just be attacking it.
Hey, next time we go over to that game center, let's...
What took you so long, Lain?
You're usually in bed now, aren't you, Lain?
Lain, don't you have anything better to wear out at night?
We'll pick out something a little more grown-up for you next time, Lain.
You think she'd look good in grown-up clothes?
Reika!
Hey...
What?
I guess the girl we saw really wasn't Lain.
That's what I've been telling you!
Lain doesn't dress like that or talk like that.
She doesn't look like that, either.
Did she really look like me?
Yeah! I was positive it was you!
Oh.
What the...?!
He's got a gun!
Help me!
Juri!
Lain!
What's she doing?
Reika, take care of Juri.
Arisu?
Arisu!
What're you looking at?
Lain, what're you doing? Let's get out of here! Hurry!
Lain!
Go away!
Why are you making me do this?!
What right do you have?!
I just wanted to clear my head, that's all!
I don't know anything about it! Leave me out of it!
You're that scattered god's...
I don't want anything to do with it! Nothing!
The Wired can't be allowed to interfere with the real world!
I don't want anything to do with it!
Who the hell are you?!
L-Lain...
I don't want anything to do with it... Don't want anything to do with it...
Don't want... I don't want... Don't want anything to do with it...
Don't want anything to...
Don't want...
Don't want anything...
Don't want anything to do with it...
Don't want... Don't want anything to do with it...
I don't want...
No matter where you go,
everyone's connected.
nan no tsumi mo nai hazu na no ni
Although I must be innocent,
nanraka no batsu wo uketeru
now I am punished.
jibun de maita tane de mo nai no ni
I wasn't the one who sowed those seeds, but nevertheless
sakimidareta hana tsumasareru
I have to pull up the flowers that bloomed from them.
shiranai koto to mo ienai ga
I can't say I didn't know about it,
katabou katsuida oboe wa nai
but I don't remember taking any part in it.
jiyuu wo takaku kawasareta ki mo suru ga
I think my freedom cost me dearly,
kokoro made yasuku utta oboe wa nai
but I don't remember selling my soul so cheaply.
Hey Hey kutabatte osaraba suru made
Hey hey, until I die and say farewell...
Hey Hey dare no te ni mo kakaranai
Hey hey... no one can touch me.
tooi yoru wo urotsuiteiru
You probably don't know
shiranai darou eien no narazu monotachi wo
the eternal outlaws prowling in the distant night.