Present Day
Present Time
And you don't seem to understand
A shame you seemed an honest man
And all the fears you hold so dear
Will turn to whisper in your ear
And you know what they say might hurt you
And you know that it means so much
And you don't even feel a thing
I am falling, I am fading
I have lost it all
I am falling, I am fading, I am drowning
Help me to breathe
I am hurting, I have lost it all
I am losing
Help me to breathe
You've heard of a girl named Lain, right?
Lain of the Wired.
Are your parents away on vacation or something?
I called the number you gave me, but no one answered.
I'm not lying.
No, I don't think you're lying. I checked.
You're Iwakura Lain, all right.
Your address and phone number check out.
It's late, so I'm going to have someone take you home.
But next time, I want you to talk to me.
Keeping quiet is a bad idea, even if you weren't involved.
For crying out loud...
Lain, I'm sorry!
This is all our fault. Are you okay, Lain?
Are you all right, Lain?
A...
What is it, Lain?
A... ri... su.
Arisu! Come on! We're going home.
Lain...
Arisu!
I'm sorry. I'm so sorry. I'm so sorry, Lain...
Tomorrow... Let's talk tomorrow, okay?
I'm sorry!
So do you want to head home, too?
A... risu.
You have a key, right?
Yes.
Message...
There are no messages for Lain.
Good night, Navi.
Good night, Lain.
Don't you think it's embarrassing for a junior high-schooler
to oversleep and be late for school?
Mom, about last night...
Hm? What about it?
Never mind.
Lain.
It's me, Lain. You can hear me, can't you?
Who's there?
You are not alone.
'Morning!
Good morning!
Oh, my god!
Was he cute?
Yeah, they wouldn't show his face on TV!
Well...
Oh, you were screaming the whole time. Did you even see his face?
Well, yeah, but...
I was a little...
You were too scared to look.
Lain!
Lain, did you get in trouble yesterday?
Come on, it wasn't really our fault.
I'm sorry. I'll be right back.
Right, Arisu was closest to the guy!
So, was there blood splattered all over?
Yeah...
Tell them!
Come on!
Arisu!
But that's not all.
If you look at the Psyche as a mere processor, you lose sight of the whole.
As a multi-purpose information terminal,
the Navi has come into wide use even among grade-schoolers.
However, activity within the Wired is currently limited by the machine.
The Psyche can dramatically increase the performance of any Navi.
There was no reason for me to stay in the real world any longer.
In the real world, it didn't matter if I was there or not.
When I realized that, I was no longer afraid of losing my body.
Who is Lain?
Huh?
There's something wrong with us!
We saw someone die right in front of us yesterday,
but we're acting like it's something we saw in a movie.
I know we were there last night, but it didn't seem real.
I guess it's like that for me, too.
I don't think you should take it so seriously, Arisu.
No, that's not what I mean.
I'm saying it's strange that we can't take it seriously.
Right, Lain?
Huh? What?
What's that, a love letter?
No way!
N-No! I don't think it is, anyway...
Let us see! Let us see!
Come on, don't be stingy! Show us!
Stop that! It's mean!
A brown paper envelope, huh?
What's written on it?
Huh?
What the heck is this?
Talk about boring!
I knew it.
Psyche...
You've got it all wrong! Somebody peeped into my voice mail!
I can't believe it!
As the relevant clauses were not in the resume we received,
we are currently discussing how to handle it. As for your company...
I love kissing. Just kissing is enough to make me happy.
You heard about that kid pulling a stupid stunt on Accela, right?
Looks like the black market supplier is freaking out.
You can't find it anywhere now.
Rumor has it that the Psyche chip is mass-produced in factories in Taiwan.
Rumor also says that it was designed by a group called the Knights.
But I'm not sure if these "Knights" even exist.
In the Wired, there are a lot of urban legends like that.
Dying feels so good!
I feel accelerated...
What the...? There's someone in my room!
It's a little person like a kid in a red and green striped shirt!
I can't move in my bed! It's standing by my door, watching me!
Help me!
I have a picture of you with your secret lover.
I just want to do business. What do you say?
If you don't buy it, I'll leak this image data to your company's server.
You'll be famous all over the Wired.
Lain, why won't you come here?
Lain has new mail.
Navi...
How's it going, Lain?
Gotten used to your new Navi?
Something wrong?
Do you know what this is?
No.
I thought...
I thought you'd know, Dad.
I said I don't know.
Come on, why not?
No... I can't...
Why not? I love you.
Lain!
Where've you been lately? I haven't seen you around.
I...
What the...? Damn, you're sure going for the "little girl" look today...
Let's have another rave, okay? I'll leave the planning to you.
Why're you trying to act so tough?
Excuse me.
Look who's talking!
Do you know what this is?
I-Is that a Psyche?!
Wha...
No way!
I've never seen one before!
W-Where did you buy it?
You know what this is?
What're you saying?
With that installed, I could get full access to the Wired with even this!
How do you use it?
Talk about lame! You don't even know that?
Can I buy it off you? Can I?
Moron! Like you could buy something like that!
What kind of Navi do you have?
I'm not really sure. It's a Tachibana.
Their newest model, I think.
Awesome!
Have you gotten inside it?
You in eighth grade? Ninth?
Eighth.
Then you've taken Basic Information, right?
A Navi's basic motherboard layout is in the textbook.
You connect it to the board, opposite the main processor.
It intercepts the original data and manipulates it on its own.
Using it is easier than building a model kit.
You just need to watch out for static electricity.
Oh. Thanks.
Hold it!
Information isn't free, not in the Wired or in the real world.
How much you gonna charge? How much?
Uh...
You're Lain, aren't you?
I saw you once. In the Wired.
You saw me? In the Wired?
You were totally different then than you are now.
Most people take on a personality in the Wired
that's different than what they have in the real world,
but yours are total opposites.
No way!
You were here when that idiot started shooting, too, weren't you?
What are you planning?
What... What should I do for you?
Go out on a date with me!
Moron.
But not like you are now.
I want the wild Lain.
I-I'm just kidding!
But if you feel like it sometime...
What're you talking about?!
Hey...
Forget about it! Let's go!
Sure!
What's so great about you?
Uh... Excuse me?
Are you here to see someone?
Who are you?
You never saw us.
W-What? I'll call the police!
We're not here, you see.
H-Hey...
W-What the hell?
Mom, if they show up again, call the cops!
Are you listening, Mom?
Damn it...
W-What're you doing, Lain?
What are you doing? Why are you dressed like that?
Well, I heard that you have to watch out for static electricity.
So I thought it'd probably be safest if I took off my clothes.
A-Are you kidding?
Welcome home, sis!
nan no tsumi mo nai hazu na no ni
Although I must be innocent,
nanraka no batsu wo uketeru
now I am punished.
jibun de maita tane de mo nai no ni
I wasn't the one who sowed those seeds, but nevertheless
sakimidareta hana tsumasareru
I have to pull up the flowers that bloomed from them.
shiranai koto to mo ienai ga
I can't say I didn't know about it,
katabou katsuida oboe wa nai
but I don't remember taking any part in it.
jiyuu wo takaku kawasareta ki mo suru ga
I think my freedom cost me dearly,
kokoro made yasuku utta oboe wa nai
but I don't remember selling my soul so cheaply.
Hey Hey kutabatte osaraba suru made
Hey hey, until I die and say farewell...
Hey Hey dare no te ni mo kakaranai
Hey hey... no one can touch me.
tooi yoru wo urotsuiteiru
You probably don't know
shiranai darou eien no narazu monotachi wo
the eternal outlaws prowling in the distant night.