Present Day
Present Time
And you don't seem to understand
A shame you seemed an honest man
And all the fears you hold so dear
Will turn to whisper in your ear
And you know what they say might hurt you
And you know that it means so much
And you don't even feel a thing
I am falling, I am fading
I have lost it all
I am falling, I am fading, I am drowning
Help me to breathe
I am hurting, I have lost it all
I am losing
Help me to breathe
Do you want to be hurt, too?
Do you want your heart to feel like it's being scraped with a rasp?
If you do, don't look away, whatever you do.
Nobody knows if there is or not.
It doesn't matter to the user if God exists in the Wired.
Just a second, Lain.
Let me take out this guy first.
What's so fun about this? All you do is kill other players.
Nobody knows what's fun and why.
"Tachibana General Laboratories" was written on the door plate.
A company as big as Tachibana General Labs wouldn't do anything illegal.
I've heard some rumors, though...
Rumors?
Do you know how we're able to exchange information in the Wired like this?
Oh, so you're testing me, huh?
You're talking about the IP.
Sorry. You're right.
We aren't usually aware of the protocol's existence.
But the current 6th-gen protocol has reached its data throughput limit.
The 7th-gen protocol...
Yes. The 7th-gen protocol.
Big companies are the ones that're making it into the new infrastructure.
To control the protocol is to control the economy of the Wired.
I hear there's constant sabotage attempts going on.
And the party behind it is...
Tachibana General Labs.
Sis?
Mom? Dad?
I...
A while ago, somebody asked me something.
"Are you Iwakura Lain? Are your parents really your parents?"
Isn't that funny?
It's funny, isn't it?
People say the funniest things, huh?
Right?
Good morning!
Arisu...
Good morning.
W-What's wrong?
I don't believe it, but...
W-What?
Lain, you didn't do it, right?
D-Didn't do what?
She's just playing innocent!
Reika! You don't know that!
Lain, seriously. It wasn't you?
What are you talking about?
Lain, in the Wired, did you...
No, forget about it. It couldn't have been you, Lain.
I trust you. Okay?
Arisu!
It's too dangerous. Avoid approving any more bills.
I can't believe it! How can such a nice guy be into such weird stuff?
There's an extremely serious bug in Protocol 6.
Damage caused by this may prove disastrous in the Wired.
Every night, a small, child-like person in a
red and green striped sweater appears in her room.
When she was in high school, that pop singer hit someone
with her boyfriend's car and fled the scene!
It's gotta be true! I heard it firsthand!
That building's a famous haunted spot.
If you look at a terminal at night,
internal e-mail shows up, but there's nobody there!
The Knights don't exist! Some American students started it as a joke!
Shut up! Who cares about any of that?
Don't you find it interesting?
Who's there?
You're looking for me, aren't you?
So God makes His grand entrance, huh?
How do you define "God"?
If it's the creator of the world, that's not me.
The all-powerful ruler of the world? You give God too much credit.
Where are you?
But if you define God as one who exists everywhere in that other world?
If that's what you mean, then yes. I suppose you could call me that.
I have only a slight influence on the workings of the world, however.
Who the hell are you?!
I am you.
You must have realized that another you has always existed in the Wired.
You are merely a hologram of that other you.
You are just a body.
You expect me to believe that?
That's impossible. It's crazy.
But you don't think that the you in the real world
is the same as the one standing here in the Wired, do you?
But I'm me...
Peeping Tom
Arisu?
Arisu? Where are you?
Arisu!
Arisu! Where are you?
Arisu, where are you? Arisu!
What did I do?
What did I do in the Wired?
What's the other me doing?
Don't worry about the rumors! Don't worry about it!
Is it all right for you to do this with a teacher?
N-No, it's not...
Why do it, then?
Because... I want to.
"Hey, do you know who Mizuki Arisu likes?"
"Do you know who she's thinking of when she plays with herself?"
It was you who told everyone! The rumors were true?!
Lain!
You've always been sitting there quietly, watching me?!
You saw what I didn't want anybody to know! When I didn't want anybody to see!
And when I...
Tell me it isn't true, Lain!
Lain!
You...
Who are you?
You're not me.
I'd never do what you do.
I...
Stop it! Why are you acting like the part of me that I hate?
You...
I'm committing suicide!
Why? Why are you warm?
Why do I have to feel your body heat?
Hey, I'm Lain, aren't I?
No!
What are these things?
They're all you.
I said that you've always existed in the Wired, didn't I?
You're the same as me.
You're omnipresent in the Wired.
Wherever anyone is, wherever they go, you have always been there.
You've watched what they didn't want others to see.
You've told everyone about it, that's all.
It was the right thing to do.
The Wired's information should be shared, shouldn't it?
Everything you say is a lie.
Why is that?
Arisu and the others said that they saw me in the Wired when I wasn't there.
As long as I'm aware of myself,
my true self is inside me!
You're telling me that these dupes are me?
What a load of garbage!
I...
If I'm really what you say I am, then...
Then what, Lain?
Their memories of being seen by Lain... I could delete that information!
That's true. Give it a try.
You were born with that kind of power.
Good morning!
Lain!
Hey, Lain!
They forgot?
They really forgot?
Lain!
They did!
Arisu!
W-What?
Hey, I wanna go to Cyberia today!
C'mon, let's go!
I second that!
Wow, this sure is unusual...
Sure. We can get changed at my place again and go from there.
Great!
Hey, what should I wear?
Stop it! I'm me!
I'm over here!
Come on, hurry up!
Hey, wait for me!
That's right! Lain is Lain, and I'm me.
Hello, Navi.
Hello, Lain.
I... I'm me, right?
There's no other me but me, right?
nan no tsumi mo nai hazu na no ni
Although I must be innocent,
nanraka no batsu wo uketeru
now I am punished.
jibun de maita tane de mo nai no ni
I wasn't the one who sowed those seeds, but nevertheless
sakimidareta hana tsumasareru
I have to pull up the flowers that bloomed from them.
shiranai koto to mo ienai ga
I can't say I didn't know about it,
katabou katsuida oboe wa nai
but I don't remember taking any part in it.
jiyuu wo takaku kawasareta ki mo suru ga
I think my freedom cost me dearly,
kokoro made yasuku utta oboe wa nai
but I don't remember selling my soul so cheaply.
Hey Hey kutabatte osaraba suru made
Hey hey, until I die and say farewell...
Hey Hey dare no te ni mo kakaranai
Hey hey... no one can touch me.
tooi yoru wo urotsuiteiru
You probably don't know
shiranai darou eien no narazu monotachi wo
the eternal outlaws prowling in the distant night.